storagecraft.com 2019-10-08

# StorageCraft Privacy Policy | StorageCraft

_Last updated: July 13, 2018_

### 1\. INTRODUCTION

This Privacy Policy (the “ **Policy** ”) explains how the StorageCraft Technology group of companies (“ **StorageCraft** ”, " **we** " or " **us** ") collect, use and share information about you. We have created this Policy in keeping with our commitment to privacy, to comply with global data protection laws and regulations, and to keep you informed about our personal information protection practices. This Policy applies to StorageCraft's collection and use of personal information belonging to people who visit our websites, employees or other personnel of our customers and/or prospective customers, and others as described herein.  

##### ABOUT US SECTION

StorageCraft provides information management and business continuity services and solutions (collectively our " **Services** ") to business customers (our " **Customers** "). In accessing our Services, our Customers may provide StorageCraft with access to business or other information that may include personal information (we refer to this as " **Customer Relationship Information** "). This Policy governs how StorageCraft processes Customer Relationship Information. In using our Cloud Products, a Customer may also provide StorageCraft with access to information in backup images that may include personal information of either our Customer or their client (we refer to this as “ **Backup Information** ”). In providing our Services, we act as the processor of **Backup Information** on behalf of, and under the instructions of, our applicable Customer. It is the responsibility of our Customer (or their respective end-customers, if any) to ensure that Backup Information that it collects, backs-up, stores, or otherwise provides StorageCraft access to, through use of our Services, has been collected lawfully and in compliance with applicable data protection laws. Please refer to the Privacy Notice of our applicable Customers for information about the ways in which they process any personal information about you contained in Backup Information.

### 2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

In general terms, we may collect personal information about you from three sources: (a) personal data you provide to us voluntarily, (b) personal data we collect automatically, and (c) personal information we receive about you from third parties. Each of these sources of personal information is explained in more detail below along with (for the benefit of individuals in the European Economic Area) StorageCraft’s legal basis for processing the personal information.  

##### (A)  Information you provide voluntarily

This is personal information that you choose to provide to us voluntarily, for example when interacting with our websites or using our products and Services. It includes details such as your name, email address, residential address, or other information permitting your identity to be directly or indirectly inferred. It will be apparent to you at the time you provide your information what information is requested, why, and whether the provision of the information is optional or mandatory.  

The following are examples of when you may choose to provide personal information to us:

  * **Trial and Evaluation Software.** If you download a free trial of StorageCraft software, you will be asked to provide your name, company name, telephone number, email address, IP address, state or province, and country. If you request a full-featured evaluation copy of our software, you will also be asked to provide your job title, address, and some general information about your organization, such as size and intended use of the evaluation software. We process this information to track who is using our trial and evaluation software and for lead generation purposes. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract to which you are a party and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract; and to further our legitimate interests, which include ensuring that use of our licensed software is not abused and managing, operating, and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Product Registration.** When you register a StorageCraft product, we collect your name, organization name, address, telephone number, and email address. We process this information to identify the end users of our software products; meeting and monitoring our contractual obligations, including licensing and delivery of maintenance and support; and marketing products and Services related to the registered product. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract; and to further our legitimate interests, which include ensuring that use of our licensed software is not abused and managing, operating, and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Product Activation.** When you activate a StorageCraft product, we collect your name, organization name and email address (optional). We may also collect some information automatically, as explained in the "Information we collect automatically" section below. We process this information to identify the end users of our software products; meet and monitor our contractual obligations, including licensing and delivery of maintenance and support; and market products and Services related to the activated product. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract; and to further our legitimate interests, which include ensuring that use of our licensed software is not abused and managing, operating, and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Agreements/Purchase Orders.** If you enter into an agreement with StorageCraft or submit a purchase order, we collect your company name, address, phone, fax, email, first name, and last name. We process this information in order to fulfill your order for products. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract and to further our legitimate interests in managing, operating and promoting our business.  
 
  * **StorageCraft Academy.** If you become a StorageCraft Academy member, we may collect your name, organization name, telephone number, billing/delivery address, and email address in order to provide you with access to the StorageCraft Academy. We may also collect the contact details of employees of your organization who you choose to register as StorageCraft Academy members. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract. In addition, we may process this information based on our legitimate interests in managing, operating and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Promotional Activities and Subscriptions.** If you choose to subscribe to newsletters, blog subscriptions, promotional emails or other online or print materials or to participate in a StorageCraft promotional event, such as a webinar, survey, sweepstakes, tradeshow, deal registration, or other promotional activity online or in any other venue, we may collect your name, company name, address, telephone number, state or province, country, postal code, and email address.  This is so that we may provide you access to an activity or provide you with information you have requested. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract. In addition, we may process this information based on our legitimate interests, which include ensuring participation by authorized participants, and managing, operating, and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Use of StorageCraft Support Community.** If you choose to use or participate in the StorageCraft Support Community, we may collect your name, nickname, email address, company name, business phone, country, mailing state, city and zip/postal code, where applicable. In addition, this information is stored, if not already present, in a contact record within Salesforce.com. StorageCraft processes this information in order to direct your needs with StorageCraft to the correct StorageCraft office. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract; and our legitimate interests, which include ensuring that appropriate users have access to our products and Services and managing, operating, and promoting our business.  

##### (B)  Information we collect automatically

This is information that we collect automatically from the devices of visitors to our websites or users of our Services. This type of information is generally collected for analytics and reporting purposes, for behavioral advertising, to improve advertising and marketing campaigns, and to maintain the security of our products, Services, and websites. The following are examples of information we collect automatically:

  * **Our Websites.** We may collect information that your browser sends to our servers when you visit our websites. For example, your browser or device may send us information about the type of browser or device you are using as well as your internet protocol (“ **IP** ”) address. When you visit a StorageCraft website, your browser may also send us information such as the page that led you to our website. In limited circumstances, depending on the search engine you are using, your browser may also send us the search terms you typed into the search engine that led you to our website. In addition, from time to time, we contract with different parties to manage our advertising on other sites. These parties may use technologies such as cookies to gather information automatically about your activities on a StorageCraft website and other sites in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. StorageCraft may also collect information using cookies and similar tracking technology. For more information, please see the section headed “Cookies and similar tracking technology” below. StorageCraft processes this information in order to understand who visits our websites and which products and Services are of most interest to them and to track proper use of the website and our Services. Our legal basis for processing this information is StorageCraft’s legitimate interests in managing, operating, and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Log Files.** To improve our Services, site functionality, or for purposes of software troubleshooting, we gather certain information automatically and through support diagnostics (upon request). This information may include IP address, browser type, internet service provider (“ **ISP** ”), referring/exit page, operating system, system name, date/time stamp, clickstream information, system settings, and/or event logs, among other system related information. StorageCraft processes this information in order to troubleshoot issues with our site functionality, software and provide technical support. Our legal basis for processing this information is StorageCraft’s legitimate interests in improving our products, Services, site functionality, troubleshooting, and/or technical support.  
 
  * **Call Records.** We also log certain telephony information when we communicate with you over the telephone such as your phone number, time and date of calls, and duration of calls. Additionally, when you contact StorageCraft, we may keep a record of your communication with us for training and quality assurance purposes. StorageCraft processes this information in order to provide and improve Services and technical support. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract; and our legitimate interests, which include improving Services, customer relations, and providing technical support.  
 
  * **Trial and Evaluation Software.** If you download a free trial of StorageCraft software, StorageCraft automatically collects certain information that may include IP address, browser type, referring/exit page, operating system, system name, and date/time stamp, among other system-related information. This is to ensure that you do not obtain multiple trial and evaluation licenses for the same machine. Our legal bases for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract; and our legitimate interests, which include managing and limiting the free use of our software.  
 
  * **Product Activation.** When you activate a StorageCraft product, we collect certain information that may include IP address, operating system, system name, date/time stamp, hardware identified, software identified, language, and product version, among other system related information. We process this information to identify the end users of our software products; meet and monitor our contractual obligations; and market products and Services related to the activated product. Our legal basis for processing this information are to perform a contract with you and/or take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract. In addition, we may process this information based on our legitimate interests, which include ensuring that use of our licensed software is not abused and managing, operating, and promoting our business.  

##### (C)  Information we receive from third parties

This is information that third parties provide to us about you, as opposed to information we collect directly from you. The following are examples of information we receive about you from third parties:

  * **Order Related Information.** If you order StorageCraft products or Services through a third-party vendor, that vendor may provide us with your order details, name, organization name, address, telephone number, and/or email address, for purposes of order fulfillment and ensuring that we can deliver our products and Services to you or someone acting on your behalf. Our legal bases for processing this information is to perform a contract with you and/or to take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract. In addition, we may process this information based on our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party vendor. In addition, we may process this information based on our legitimate interests in managing, operating and promoting our business.  
 
  * **Information from Partners.** We may also receive your name, organization name, address, telephone number, and/or email address, from third parties with whom we market our products or Services (i.e., a trade show, webinar, third-party advertisement, white paper) and/or to whom we distribute our products and Services. Where we have appropriate rights to do so we will process this information in order to contact potential customers. Our legal basis for processing this information is our legitimate interests in promoting our business to parties who have expressed an interest in StorageCraft products or Services or products or services like those offered by StorageCraft.  
 
  * **Information from Social Media Platforms.** If you choose to engage with StorageCraft via a social media account or channel, we may receive certain information about you from your applicable social media provider. Exactly what information we might receive will depend on your social media privacy settings, but will typically include your basic profile information and email address. We will process this information in order to understand how you engage with our Services. Our legal basis for processing this information is our legitimate interests in understanding how our Customers and prospective customers engage with our Services.  
 
  * **Information from Applicants.** We may also receive your name, organization name, telephone number, and/or email address, from an applicant seeking employment with StorageCraft for purposes of contacting you for a professional reference. Our legal basis for processing this information is our legitimate interests in assuring that we hire the most qualified individuals for a particular role.

### 3\. SECURING AND STORING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We understand that the security of your personal information is important. We provide appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security controls to protect your personal information. We use appropriate security measures on our websites and in our products and Services to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information in our control. These security measures include use of Secure Socket Layer (“ **SSL** ”), firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention, network monitoring, physical and site security, encryption, and passwords. The Internet, however, is an open environment and information may flow across various networks, some of which employ inadequate security measures, resulting in unauthorized access to information. Transmission of such information is therefore entirely at your own risk. While it is impossible to protect a website or an online product or service completely, StorageCraft works hard to keep your information safe.

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone, you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

If we store information you provide to us, we do so on our secure servers. Details relating to any transactions are transmitted using SSL technology.

StorageCraft will not view the contents of the backup images or files you store using a StorageCraft cloud product unless you request us to for technical support and then only if we are able. StorageCraft and/or its products, however, may access file folder names, file extensions, file size information, and the like in order to deliver cloud products and associated technical support to you.

### 4\. SPECIAL CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

StorageCraft does not seek to collect or process sensitive personal information and takes affirmative action to avoid the inadvertent collection or processing of such information. If sensitive personal information is provided to StorageCraft by a Customer (or you acting on behalf of a Customer), StorageCraft will process such information in order to provide its cloud products to the Customer and only as instructed by the Customer.

### 5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may disclose your personal information to the following categories of recipients:

  * To our **corporate affiliates, third party service providers** and **partners** who process your personal information when assisting us in conducting our business, providing you with our products or Services, or offering our products or Services. These third parties may not use your information for purposes other than these.  
 
  * To an **actual or potential buyer (and its agents and advisers)** , if, for strategic or other business reasons, StorageCraft decided to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize any part of its business in any countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure or transfer to prospective or actual purchasers of personal information that StorageCraft, or its designee, has in its possession. Should such a sale, merger, or transfer occur, we will inform the transferee to use your personal information in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy.  
 
  * To any **competent law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party** where we believe such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with the law, including an order of any competent court; (b) protect and defend the rights, interests or property of StorageCraft or any other person (including in connection the enforcement of our agreements); (c) protect your safety or the safety of others; (d) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; (e) act in urgent circumstances or emergencies; or (f) provide the products or Services we have agreed to provide to you or to those you have asked to act on your behalf.  
 
  * To any **other person, when you agree and consent to such sharing** , or when disclosure is necessary to deliver the products or Services you have contracted to receive from us.

### 6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

If you are an individual from the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ), the information that we collect from you, including personal information relating to you or Customer Relationship Information that we process in providing a Service, may be transferred to, and processed by, StorageCraft’s corporate affiliates and service providers outside the EEA for the purposes described in this Policy. Our corporate affiliates and service providers operate around the world.

These affiliates and service providers may be based in territories whose data protection laws are different from those of the country or region in which you are based, but we will always protect your personal information in accordance with this Policy. In addition, we will protect transfers to countries outside the EEA with appropriate safeguards, such as using standard contractual clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission or by certification with the US-EU and/or US-Switzerland Privacy Shield regime.

Further details can be provided upon request.

### 7\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

 If you are a resident of the EEA you have the following data protection rights with regard to the processing of your personal information:

  * The right to access to your personal information processed by StorageCraft.
  * The right to rectification of personal information held by StorageCraft where it is incomplete or inaccurate.
  * The right, in some circumstances, to erasure (“right to be forgotten”) of personal information.
  * The right, in some circumstances, to restrict StorageCraft’s processing of your personal information.
  * The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority concerning our processing of your personal information.
  * To the extent StorageCraft’s processing of your personal information is based on consent, the right to withdraw such consent. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * The right to object to StorageCraft’s processing of your personal information where such processing is based on legitimate interests.
  * The right to opt-out of StorageCraft’s processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.
  * Where certain conditions are met, the right to have your personal information provided in a machine-readable format and that you may transmit to another controller.  

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

You can exercise any of the above rights at any time by contacting us using the details in Section 16 below.

### 8\.  USE OF COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGY

StorageCraft uses cookie technology (" **Cookies** ") to collect and use personal information about you, including to serve interest based advertising. For more information about the types of Cookies we use, why we use them, and how you can control Cookies, please see our Cookie Policy.

### 9\. THIRD PARTY SITES

From time to time, our website may contain links to third party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. We recommend and encourage that you always review the privacy policies of third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties.

### 10\. SOCIAL MEDIA

As outlined above, our website may include social media features, such as buttons, tools, or content that link to other companies’ services, (e.g. a Facebook "Like" button). When you interact with these features, information that you have entered into the social media platform may be passed along to us. In addition, when you see or interact with these buttons, tools, or content, or view a StorageCraft website containing them, some information from your browser may automatically be sent to the provider of the social media service. Please read the relevant social media privacy policy of the respective provider for more information regarding its use of that information.

### 11\. ACCESSING AND UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION

StorageCraft gives you access to a range of information about your account and your interactions with StorageCraft. If you are a user of a StorageCraft web portal, you can view much of the information we have about you. You can also write to us at [privacy@eu.storagecraft.com](mailto:privacy@eu.storagecraft.com) to obtain the information we have about you, as well as change, update or request deletion of that information. To protect your privacy and security, we may require that you complete certain steps to verify your identity before granting you access to your information. 

### 12\. COLLECTION AND USE OF CHILDREN’S PERSONAL INFORMATION

StorageCraft does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If StorageCraft learns that we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our systems. We encourage you to talk with your children about communicating with strangers and disclosing personal information online.

### 13\. DATA RETENTION

Please note that we need to retain certain personal information about you and our Customers where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so. This for example might include providing you or our Customer with a Service you have requested, to comply with legal or other internal business requirements, such as fraud prevention and accounting purposes. In addition, we retain backup images that our enterprise customers store with us through our cloud products for the duration they instruct.

We will retain and use personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, protect rights and enforce our agreements. Although it is not always possible to delete all instances of an individual’s personal information from all backup media, our backup media is protected by robust physical security measures, as well as encryption, and is disposed of securely when the media is retired.

### 14\. COMMUNICATIONS PREFERENCES

If you do not wish to receive certain communications from StorageCraft, you may send an email to the email address for your geographical region identified in Section 16 below to tell us which communications you prefer. Alternatively, you can click on the unsubscribe link that is included in any promotional or marketing e-mails that we may send to you from time to time.

### 15\. MODIFICATIONS TO THIS POLICY

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time. If we make any material changes to this Policy, we will endeavor to provide you with advance notice of this, for example by posting a notice on our website or (where appropriate) through more direct means, such as e-mail. Your continued use of any portion of this website after the “last update” date, which is the effective date of any such changes, will constitute your acceptance of those changes. Please check our websites for the most current version.

### 16\. HOW TO CONTACT US

We welcome any queries, comments or requests you may have regarding this Privacy Policy, or about our privacy practices in general. If you wish to contact us, you can do so by the following means:

_**If you are an individual resident in the United States:**_ Please contact us in writing at StorageCraft Technology Corporation, 380 Data Drive, Suite 300, Draper, UT 84020, Attn: Legal or by e-mail at [privacy@storagecraft.com](mailto:privacy@storagecraft.com); or

**_If you are an individual resident outside of the United States:_** Please contact us in writing at StorageCraft Technology, Tellengana House, Blackrock Road, Cork, Ireland, Attn: Legal or by e-mail at [privacy@eu.storagecraft.com](mailto:privacy@storagecraft.com).

If you are a resident of the EEA StorageCraft Technology is the data controller of your personal data (other than any personal information contained within Backup Information that StorageCraft hosts on behalf of its Customers, in respect of which the relevant Customer or its customer is the data controller). You can contact StorageCraft Technology using the details provided above.
